Tucson Audubon Society records, 1944-[ongoing]
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Tucson Audubon Society Records 1944-[ongoing]
MS 368
Tucson Audubon Society
The Tucson Audubon Society records contains business records, Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, and administrative correspondence; materials about conservation issues and educational programs; case studies, and a complete set of newsletters documenting the history and development of the organization.
8 linear feet
Main Library Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Historical Note
In January 1949, Tucson Audubon Society was organized to promote the appreciation and preservation of wildlife. The Tucson Chapter, incorporated in 1964, is dedicated to improving the quality of the environment by providing education, conservation, and recreation programs. Field trips, ecology camps, workshops and conservation activities increase knowledge, and awareness of our environment. Education and advocacy of conservation issues in Arizona, and Sonora, Mexico, are their highest priority.
Organization
This collection is organized into five series:
Series I. Administration, 1961-1996
Series II. Conservation, 1944-1987
Series III. Education, 1969-1971
Series IV. Organization, 1949-1994
Series V. Publications, 1949-2000
Scope and Content Note
Series One, Administration, contains correspondence of the officers, board of directors meeting materials, and documents of committees. Series Two, Conservation, consists of case studies and issues of concern. Interactions with other conservation entities are documented in publications and correspondence. Series Three, Education, consists of brochures, planning materials, correspondence, itineraries, postcards and photographs of events. Field trips, Camp of the West, Family Institute and Desert Safari are included with particular emphasis on the Institute of Desert Ecology. Series Four, Organization, contains national, regional, state and chapter materials regarding cooperative efforts and interests. Publications (1949 - 2000), contains two published copies of The Road-Runner, and correspondence reflecting the planning for publication of Birds of Southeastern Arizona. Newsletters, preserved since the founding of the Tucson Audubon Society in 1957, are included. The complete set of this newsletter, officially known as The Vermillion Flycatcher and published since 1959, offers an ongoing record of the membership, activities and accomplishments of this strong and growing organization.
National Audubon Society; Tucson Audubon Society -- Archives; Sierra Club; Arizona Water Commission; Arizonans for Water without Waste; Institute of Desert Ecology; Human ecology; Wilderness areas -- Arizona; Conservation of natural resources -- Arizona; Wildlife refuges -- Arizona; Birds -- Conservation; Wild and scenic rivers; Coronado National Forest (Ariz. and N.M.); Death Valley National Park (Calif. and Nev.); Dragoon Mountains (Ariz.); Imperial National Wildlife Refuge (Ariz. and Calif.); Kofa National Wildlife Refuge (Ariz.); Madera Canyon (Ariz.); Montezuma Castle (Ariz.); Tuzigoot National Monument (Ariz.); Organ Pipe Cactus National Monument (Ariz.); Saguaro National Park (Ariz.); Salt River (Ariz.: River); San Francisco River (Ariz. and N.M.); Wupatki National Monument (Ariz.); Zion National Park (Utah); Apache National Forest (Ariz. and N.M.); Ramsey Canyon (Ariz.); San Pedro River (Mexico and Ariz.); Newsletters; Business records; Correspondence; Brochures; Postcards
Container List
- Series I: Administration, 1961-1996
  - Administration--Board of Directors--Correspondence, 1983-1986 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Administration--Board of Directors--Legal Responsibilities, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Administration--Board of Directors--Meetings, January 1949-April 1959 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Administration--Board of Directors--Meetings, 1960-1964 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Administration--Board of Directors--Meetings, 1965-1970 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Administration--Board of Directors--Meetings, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Administration--Board of Directors--Meetings, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Administration--Board of Directors--Meetings, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Administration--Board of Directors--Meetings, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Administration--Board of Directors--Meetings, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Administration--Board of Directors--Meetings, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Administration--Board of Directors--Meetings, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Administration--Board of Directors--Meetings, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Administration--Board of Directors--Meetings, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Administration--Board of Directors--Meetings, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Administration--Board of Directors--Meetings, 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Administration--Board of Directors--Meetings, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Administration--Board of Directors--Meetings, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Administration--Board of Directors--Meetings, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Administration--Board of Directors--Meetings, 1988-1991 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Administration--Board of Directors--Meetings, 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Administration--Committees--Collecting, 1971-1976 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Administration--Committees--Conservation, May 1982-May 1983 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Administration--Committees--Conservation--Census, 1969-1996 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Administration--Committees--Education, 1967-1992 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Administration--Committees--Education--Field Trips, 1965-1984 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Administration--Committees--Education--Field Trips--Mexican Tours, 1966-1985 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Administration--Committees--Education--Institutes, 1971-1983 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Administration--Committees--Finance, 1980-1993 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Administration--Committees--Chalif Memorial Fund (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Administration--Committees--Fincance--Donations--Correspondence, 1980-1993 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Administration--Committees--Finance--Fundraising--Birdathon, 1984-1989 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Administration--Committees--Finance--Fundraising--Ideas, 1981-1993 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Administration--Committees--Finance--Fundraising--Photo Contest, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Administration--Committees--Finance--Fundraising--Silent Auction, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Administration--Committees--Finance--Grants, Scholarships, Awards--Correspondence, 1975-1989 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Administration--Committees--Finance--Grants, Scholarships, Awards--Proposals, 1975-1977 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Administration--Committees--Finance--Grants, Scholarships, Awards--Proposals, 1980-1984 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Administration--Committees--Finance--Nature Shop, 1978-1986 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Administration--Committees--Finance--Thornburg Memorial Fund, 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Administration--Committees--Newsletter, 1969-1996 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Administration--Committees--Publicity, 1970-1987 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Administration--Committees--Publicity (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Administration--Executive Director, 1982-1988 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Administration--Membership--Dinner Meetings, 1983-1987 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Administration--Office--Insurance, 1981-1988 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Administration--Officers--Correspondence, 1961-1990 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Administration--Officers--Presidents--Edward Chalif, 1971-1991 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Administration--Officers--Presidents--William Harrison--Correspondence 1968-1970 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Series II: Conservation, 1944-1971
  - Conservation--Case Studies--Coronado National Forest, 1970-1971 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Conservation--Case Studies--Coronado National Forest, 1972-1975 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Conservation--Case Studies--Coronado National Forest, 1976-1978 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Conservation--Case Studies--Coronado National Forest, March 1983-May 1983 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Conservation--Case Studies--Coronado National Forest (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Conservation--Case Studies--Coronado National Forest--Maps, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Conservation--Case Studies--Coronado National Forest Publications, May 1985 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Conservation--Case Studies--Coronado National Memorial, 1944-1969 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Conservation--Case Studies--Death Valley National Monument, 1965-1974 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Conservation--Case Studies--Death Valley National Monument--Brochures (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Conservation--Case Studies--Death Valley National Monument--Postcards (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Conservation--Case Studies--Dragoon Mountains, 1972-1978 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Conservation--Case Studies--Dragoon Mountains, 1978-1983 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Conservation--Case Studies--Dragoon Mountains, January 1984-March 1984 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Conservation--Case Studies--Dragoon Mountains--Maps (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Conservation--Case Studies--Imperial Wildlife Refuge, January 1972-August 1972 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Conservation--Case Studies--Imperial Wildlife Refuge--Publications (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Conservation--Case Studies--Kofa Game Range, 1972-1976 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Conservation--Case Studies--Madera Canyon, August 1987 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Conservation--Case Studies--Montezuma Castle/Tuzigoot National Monuments, July 1974-September 1974 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Conservation--Case Studies--Needles Wilderness Public Hearing, December 10-11, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Conservation--Case Studies---Organ Pipe Cactus National Monument, 1972-1973 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Conservation--Case Studies---Organ Pipe Cactus National Monument, January 1974-February 1974 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Conservation--Case Studies---Organ Pipe Cactus National Monument, February 1974-February 1979 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Conservation--Case Studies---Organ Pipe Cactus National Monument--Pamphlets (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Conservation--Case Studies---Organ Pipe Cactus National Monument--Publications, 1975-1977 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Conservation--Case Studies---Organ Pipe National Monument--Publications, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Conservation--Case Studies---Organ Pipe National Monument (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Conservation--Case Studies--Saguaro National Monument, 1971-1972 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Conservation--Case Studies--Saguaro National Monument, 1973-1978 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Conservation--Case Studies--Saguaro National Monument--Final Environmental Statement, May 1975 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Conservation--Case Studies--Saguaro National Monument--National and Cultural Resources Management Plan, 1979-1980 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Conservation--Case Studies--Salt River, June 1982 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Conservation--Case Studies--San Francisco River, July 1982 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Conservation--Case Studies--Sequoia and Kings Canyon--Giant Forest Lodgepole Complex, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Conservation--Case Studies--Wupatki National Monument, 1970-1971 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Conservation--Case Studies--Zion National Park, Utah, 1973-1974 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Conservation--Issues--Arizona, 1969-1989 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Conservation--Issues--Arizona--Apache National Forest, 1971-1974 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Conservation--Issues--Arizona--Apache National Forest, 1975-1977 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Conservation--Issues--Arizona--Clarksdale--Williams Highway, 1970-1976 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Conservation--Issues--Arizona--Patagonia--Sonoita Creek Sanctuary, 1955-1967 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Conservation--Issues--Arizona--Pesticides, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Conservation--Issues--Arizona--Ramsey Canyon/Mount Graham, November 1987 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Conservation--Issues--Arizona--Rare Bird Alert, 1975-1987 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Conservation--Issues--Arizona--San Pedro/Santa Cruz, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Conservation--Issues--National, 1966-1969 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Conservation--Issues--National, 1972-1989 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Conservation--Issues--National--Wildlife Refuges, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Conservation--Issues--New Mexico, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Conservation--Issues--Regional, 1972-1988 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Conservation--Issues--Wild and Scenic Rivers, 1978-1981 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Conservation--Issues--Wilderness Hearings, 1971-1972 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Conservation--Issues--Wilderness Hearings, 1973-1976 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Conservation--Other Organizations--Arizona Water Commission, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Conservation--Other Organizations--Arizonans For Water Without Waste, 1969-1971 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Conservation--Other Organizations--Sierra Club, 1968-1974 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Series III: Education, 1969-1991
  - Education--Camp of the West, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Education--Desert Safari, 1969-1972 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Education--Family Institute, 1978-1987 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Education--Field Trips, 1983-1994 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Education--Information Packet, 1986-1987 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Education--Institute of Desert Ecology, 1970-1975 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Education--Institute of Desert Ecology, 1976-1979 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Education--Institute of Desert Ecology, 1980-1996 (Box 9, Folder 11)
- Series IV: Organization, 1949-1994
  - Organization--Arizona Audubon--Activists, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Organization--Council, 1983-1988 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Organization--National Audubon, 1964-1982 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Organization-- National Audubon, 1983-1988 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Organization--National Audubon--Regional Conference, August 4-10, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Organization--Tucson Chapter--Chapter Certification, 1986-1990 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Organization--Tucson Chapter--History, 1949-1988 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Organization--Tucson Chapter--History (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Organization--Tucson Chapter--Membership, 1963-1983 (Box 9, Folder 20)
- Series V: Publications, 1951-2001
  - Publications--Correspondence-- Birds of Southeastern Arizona, 1984-1994 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Publications--Newsletters, 1957 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Publications--Newsletters, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Publications--Newsletters, 1959 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Publications--Newsletters, 1960 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Publications--Newsletters, 1961 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Publications--Newsletters, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Publications--Newsletters, 1963 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Publications--Newsletters, 1964 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Publications--Newsletters, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Publications--Newsletters, 1966 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Publications--Newsletters, 1967 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Publications--Newsletters, 1968 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Publications--Newsletters, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Publications--Newsletters, 1970 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Publications--Newsletters, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Publications--Newsletters, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Publications--Newsletters, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Publications--Newsletters, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Publications--Newsletters, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Publications--Newsletters, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Publications--Newsletters, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Publications--Newsletters, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Publications--Newsletters, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Publications--Newsletters, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Publications--Newsletters, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Publications--Newsletters, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Publications--Newsletters, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Publications--Newsletters, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Publications--Newsletters, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Publications--Newsletters, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Publications--Newsletters, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Publications--Newsletters, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Publications--Newsletters, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Publications--Newsletters, 1990 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Publications--Newsletters, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Publications--Newsletters, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Publications--Newsletters, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Publications--Newsletters, 1994 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Publications--Newsletters, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Publications--Newsletters, 1996 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Publications--Newsletters, 1997 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Publications--Newsletters, 1998 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Publications--Newsletters, 1999 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Publications--Newsletters, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Publications-- The Road-runner, 1949-1951 (Box 12, Folder 11)